<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>UCSB NLP Blog - Alon Albalak</title><link href="nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/feeds/alon-albalak.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/</id><updated>2024-02-29T06:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>A new guide for the responsible development of foundation models</title><link href="nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/a-new-guide-for-the-responsible-development-of-foundation-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-29T06:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-29T06:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Alon Albalak</name></author><id>tag:None,2024-02-29:nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/a-new-guide-for-the-responsible-development-of-foundation-models.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Announcing the Foundation Model Development Cheatsheet!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;The Foundation Model Development Cheatsheet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
  &lt;img src="images/fmcheatsheet/cheatsheet-0.png" width="30%" alt="The Foundation Model Development Cheatsheet"&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landscape of foundation models is experiencing a &lt;em&gt;rapid&lt;/em&gt; evolution, marked by a burgeoning community of developers and contributors, leading to significant advances in the capabilities of these models. Amidst this incredible progress it is important to ensure that the development of models is done responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;UCSB NLP&lt;/strong&gt;, we are committed to fostering the development of foundation models &lt;strong&gt;responsibly, openly, collaboratively&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;ethically&lt;/strong&gt;. We recognize that the responsible development of foundation models is essential to ensuring that these models are used to benefit society.
In line with our goals, we have actively encouraged and participated in open progress by developing &lt;strong&gt;datasets&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2304.06939.pdf"&gt;mmc4&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;surveys&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.16827"&gt;Data selection survey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2308.03188"&gt;Self-correcting LLMs&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;benchmarks&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://github.com/matt-seb-ho/WikiWhy"&gt;WikiWhy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://finqasite.github.io/"&gt;FinQA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://alon-albalak.github.io/feta-website/"&gt;FETA&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/sharonlevy/SafeText"&gt;SafeText&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://tabfact.github.io/"&gt;TabFact&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://eric-xw.github.io/vatex-website/index.html"&gt;VaTeX&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;strong&gt;tools to evaluate models&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://github.com/xu1998hz/InstructScore_SEScore3"&gt;InstructScore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://saxon.me/coco-crola/"&gt;CoCo-CroLa&lt;/a&gt;), and &lt;strong&gt;models&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://github.com/apple/ml-mgie"&gt;mgie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2205.14268"&gt;NeuPSL&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a next step in our mission, we aim to &lt;strong&gt;lower the barrier to entry for new developers&lt;/strong&gt;. In this spirit, we are thrilled to introduce the &lt;strong&gt;"Foundation Model Development Cheatsheet"&lt;/strong&gt;, a concise guide containing resources, tools, and findings from researchers at UCSB and ten other leading organizations. Written &lt;em&gt;by&lt;/em&gt; foundation model developers &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; foundation model developers, the cheat sheet is designed as a quick-start guide for new developers to familiarize themselves with the essential tools and resources for the responsible development of foundation models across text, vision, and speech modalities. The cheat sheet covers the full lifecycle of model development including: data collection, preprocessing, and documentation; model pretraining and finetuning; environmental impact estimation; assessing risks and harms; as well as model documentation, release, and licensing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this resource will be useful for new developers and experienced researchers alike, as a way of raising awareness for responsible model development.
Explore the &lt;a href="https://github.com/allenai/fm-cheatsheet/blob/main/app/resources/paper.pdf"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; for more details, and find cheatsheet resources that are relevant for you on the &lt;a href="https://fmcheatsheet.org/"&gt;project website&lt;/a&gt;. The cheatsheet is a living document and will continue to be updated—anyone is welcome to contribute resources directly &lt;a href="https://github.com/allenai/fm-cheatsheet?tab=readme-ov-file#add-to-cheatsheet"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and will be recognized for contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~Alon&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Announcements"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="foundation models"></category><category term="responsible AI"></category></entry></feed>