<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>UCSB NLP Blog - Announcements</title><link href="nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/feeds/announcements.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/</id><updated>2021-10-15T12:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>UC Santa Barbara NLP Group Recruiting Ph.D. Students for 2022!</title><link href="nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/uc-santa-barbara-nlp-group-recruiting-phd-students-for-2022.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-10-15T12:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-10-15T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>William Yang Wang</name></author><id>tag:None,2021-10-15:nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/uc-santa-barbara-nlp-group-recruiting-phd-students-for-2022.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Come join us at the UCSB NLP Group as a new Ph.D. student!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Multiple Ph.D. Positions in NLP/AI/ML at UCSB!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!Fig!8!
&lt;img alt="zero-shot-fact-verification" class="img-fluid" src="images/ucsb_aerial.jpg"&gt;
Come join us at the UCSB NLP Group as a new Ph.D. student!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Computer Science Department at University of California, Santa Barbara invites applications for multiple PhD student positions in Natural Language Processing, Artificial Intelligence, and Machine Learning. &lt;a href="http://nlp.cs.ucsb.edu"&gt;UCSB Natural Language Processing Group&lt;/a&gt; includes Profs. &lt;a href="https://code-terminator.github.io/"&gt;Shiyu Chang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://lileicc.github.io/"&gt;Lei Li&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://sjtodd.github.io/"&gt;Simon Todd&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://sites.cs.ucsb.edu/~william/"&gt;William Wang&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://sites.cs.ucsb.edu/~xyan/"&gt;Xifeng Yan&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are looking for students who are:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-motivated&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passionate about advancing AI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proficienct programmers and problem solvers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathematically mature and proficient in ML-relevant statistical methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Familiar with deep learning frameworks such as TensorFlow, PyTorch, or MXNet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UC Santa Barbara is a &lt;a href="https://www.news.ucsb.edu/2021/020393/top-five"&gt;Top 5 U.S. Public Research University&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://csrankings.org/"&gt;the UCSB NLP Group ranked #4 in the most productive NLP groups in 2018-2021 in America&lt;/a&gt;. Recent UCSB CS and NLP PhD graduates and postdocs have taken tenure-track faculty positions at prestigious schools such as UIUC, UCSD, Waterloo, UChicago, UT Austin, UMich, Dartmouth, Purdue, Virginia Tech, OSU, UCSC, Northeastern, and Rochester. Our PhD students were placed into top industry internship positions during Summer, including Facebook AI Research, Google AI, Microsoft Research, Salesforce, Amazon etc. UCSB boasts to be &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/106330614"&gt;one of the most beautiful campuses in the world&lt;/a&gt; with perfect weather year round. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UCSB’s international scholar office will provide support for visa, and we will provide top academic PhD student salary, health insurance, benefits, and travel budget for conferences. Qualified candidates may directly apply to UCSB’s CS PhD program and indicate faculty of interest in the personal statement and the application system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLEASE NOTE: The UCSB Computer Science department has eliminated the GRE requirement for Fall 2022 applicants.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://cs.ucsb.edu/education/graduate/overview"&gt;More information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Announcements"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="about"></category></entry><entry><title>Introducing the UC Santa Barbara NLP Blog!</title><link href="nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/introducing-the-uc-santa-barbara-nlp-blog.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-31T16:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-31T16:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Michael Saxon</name></author><id>tag:None,2021-07-31:nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/blog/introducing-the-uc-santa-barbara-nlp-blog.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A short post introducing our new blog.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;A short introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very exciting new year for the UCSB NLP Group. We are welcoming several new &lt;a href="http://nlp.cs.ucsb.edu/people.html"&gt;faculty members and Ph.D. students&lt;/a&gt;, and continuing to grow our research efforts! In light of this growth, we feel it is important to put together a single place to consolidate and share updates about our projects, publications, and members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end, we are very excited to share the new UCSB NLP Blog and Twitter pages that we will be using to share in-depth, but slightly more informal introductions of our new work as it is released!  Please follow us on Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ucsbNLP"&gt;@ucsbNLP&lt;/a&gt; to see our updates when they are posted!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Announcements"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="about"></category></entry></feed>